Mary Njeri Nyoro

Motivated young woman who is actively interested in women empowerment especially women in Math related fields and Technology. I have experience in the Insurance industry specifically in InsurTech with a proven ability to work with difficult situations. Currently pursuing a degree in Computer Science.

CONTACT DETAILS



mnyoro17@alustudent.com



+254708086321



Nairobi, Kenya

EDUCATION

2017- Present

COMPUTER SCIENCE African Leadership University (ALU)

Relevant Coursework: Programming languages, (Java, Python, C, Html, Css, Java Script), Human • Computer Interaction, Technology and Society, Software Engineering, Website Development.

SKILLS

Data Analytics Marketing Adaptability Market Research

INTEREST(S)

Women in Tech Fashion Social media management Marketing

LANGUAGE(S)

English -Fluent Kiswahili - Fluent

WORK EXPERIENCE

MARKETING RESEARCH AND BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT INTERN INTERN

Jauntin (insur-tech), Canada: July 2019 - September 2019

- Conducted deep research on the company and gave insights by analysing big data and running reports.
- Managed Jauntins' social media, especially Twitter, where I created content that was approved by the CEO and posted weekly.

INSURANCE AGENT INTERN NIC Bank, Kenya: June 2018 - August 2018

- Collaborated with a team of 4 on reconciliation, that is, tracing payments from 2015 and sending invoices to the corresponding underwriters in order to pay back to the bank.
- Interacted on a day to day basis with the bank's system where I Filled in customer details concerning Insurance.

TECH INTERN

African Leadership University, Rwanda: October 2018 - Current

- Offer full support to Students, Staff and Faculty members at the University regarding technical issues.
- Came up with a concrete system of processes where Students, staff, and faculty can request for various items during big and small events happening on campus or off campus.
- · Documentation of all Tech support needs in the University.

EXTRACURRICULAR/ LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

CO-FOUNDER

Mariru: July 2019 - Present

With a team of 2, we work on combining fashion and sustainability. We have an online thrift store which is currently on Instagram to provide fashionable and sustainable clothes for women